<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>rsegebre</title><link>http://rsegebre.com</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://rsegebre.com/feeds/all.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>New Blog/Website</title><link>http://rsegebre.com/new-blogwebsite.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first attemp to setup my new personal website/blog following pydanny's steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="update"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2012-06-13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after a couple of days of playing around I am finally getting used to this,
also if you've never used &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docutils.sourceforge.net/rst.html"&gt;ReST&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.latex-project.org"&gt;Latex&lt;/a&gt;, it might be somewhat annoying.
But the basics are not that hard to learn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roberto Segebre</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://rsegebre.com/new-blogwebsite.html</guid><category>blog</category><category>pydanny</category><category>website</category></item><item><title>Welcome!</title><link>http://rsegebre.com/welcome.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So now that is summer and I just graduated, I realize I finally
have enough time to get a website rolling. So I starting looking
into what simple blog engine that allows for quite some modification
and custom themes. So I came across &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.notmyidea.org"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; after going through some
static blog generators, and coming across &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com"&gt;Pydanny&lt;/a&gt;'s Website, I decided
on Pelican. Yeah if you click on pydanny's website you'll see that they basically
look exactly the same. That is because I just followed his as a template
and we are both using the same pelican theme. Also Pydanny's website contains
a good article on all the different &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/choosing-a-new-python-based-blog-engine.html"&gt;static blog generators&lt;/a&gt; and how to run your &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pydanny.com/my-new-blog.html"&gt;own
pelican website&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting something decent going on in my own lil virtual box, I went to
try and deploy it. Which I knew would be the most annoying phase, since you have to
deal with various elements. Such as: your registrar, creating A records, waiting
for DNS servers to update and countless hours googling ;). But it
payed off, I will write a guide later on about how to roll your own Pelican website using github for free! (unless you want to have your own domain name)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways my head is killing from staring at the screen(s) too long! So I am going to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyaa!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~rs&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Roberto Segebre</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://rsegebre.com/welcome.html</guid><category>blog</category><category>pydanny</category><category>pelican</category><category>website</category></item></channel></rss>